



© Contact

□Email: ammarhanyezeldin@gmail.com

► Phone:
 +46 739 793 588
 +90 539 577 59 90
 +20 106 188 84 76

Experienced Computer and Software Engineer with an interest in AI, Computer Vision, and Backend, specializing in AI, Computer Vision, Backend, and IoT. Proficient in Python and C#. I have over 3 years of experience. Currently seeking full-time opportunities in Software Engineering Roles, I am open to remote, hybrid, or on-site positions with relocation availability.

| Skills                  |  |
|-------------------------|--|
| Programming Languages   | C#, Python, C++, Java, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, XAML   |
| Frontend Frameworks     | Bootstrap  |
| Backend Frameworks      | Flask, ASP.NET, Entity Framework, MVC, Razor, Blazor, Laravel, .NET, REST API, JSON, YAML, .ENV, Node.js   |
| Desktop Frameworks      | WPF  |
| Database Technologies   | MySQL, MSSQL, SQLite, Firebase   |
| Mobile Frameworks       | Android  |
| Al Frameworks           | TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, OpenCV, Ultralytics, Supervision, YOLO   |
| Python Libraries        | NumPy, Pandas, OS, Shutil, JWT, Gunicorn, PIL, glob, hashlib, google.cloud   |
| Cloud Services          | Google Cloud Platform  |
| DevOps Tools            | Docker, Artifact Registry  |
| Applications and Tools  | VSCode, Visual Studio, PyCharm, Android Studio, IntelliJ, Wix, Fl Studio, Microsoft Office, CMake, Postman, SSH, VM  |
| Fields and Technologies | Full-Stack, Al, Mobile Development, Web Development, Database Management, DevOps, REST Apis, Backend Development, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Version Control, Cloud Computing, Game Industry |
| Languages               | English (C2), Turkish (B2), Arabic (Native), Swedish (A1), French (A1)   |
| Skills                  | Quick Learner, Attention to Detail, <b>Problem Solving</b> , Creativity, Teamwork, Mentorship, Leadership  |

# **Work Experience**

Mid-Level Software Engineer | Animals Animals.Al

Helsingborg, Sweden | 08/2023 - 04/2024

- Developed 30+ advanced Computer Vision Models and 50+ image processing algorithms.
- Managed annotation tasks for over 10,000 images.
- Automated model training using Google Compute Engine, including automatic data downloading, training, and model deployment.
- Managed backend infrastructure on Google Cloud Platform, overseeing Firebase and Cloud Run for storage systems.
- Designed and optimized **REST APIs**, facilitating team efficiency.
- Composed an automated camera system with up to 12 cameras for AI scripts and IoT solutions.
- Worked with 5+ Nvidia Jetson devices on one network, leveraging RTSP technologies.
- Mentored 3+ interns in API development, backend engineering, and computer vision techniques.
- Acquired extensive knowledge of agriculture practices through IoT work, 5+ farm visits, and collaboration with 4+ researchers and engineers.

## Internship in IT | Toros University

Mersin, Turkey | 03/2023 - 07/2023

- Maintained the company's IT infrastructure. Fixed about **50**% of the laboratory's computers.
- Ensured that they were prepared for use by thousands of students.
- Assisted the professors with all their technical problems with a 100% satisfaction rate.

## Internship in IT | Toros University

Mersin, Turkey | **07/2022 – 09/2022** 

Gained experience in a variety of IT tasks, including software development, system administration, and network engineering.

#### Freelance | Full Stack Web Development

Mersin, Turkey | 09/2021 - 09/2022

- Able to work independently to meet deadlines and deliver projects on time and within budget.
- Collaborated with marketing agencies for developing their websites while including SEO.

# **Education**

#### Toros University | Bachelor of Computer and Software Engineering

Mersin, Turkey | 09/2019 - 07/2023

- Ranked 1<sup>st</sup> Student on Computer and software Engineering Department and Engineering Faculty and Ranked 2<sup>nd</sup> on the whole University.
- GPA: 3.77/4.00. Passed all semesters with honors. (Transcript)
- Member of administrative board in Computer Sciences Community
- Graduation Project: Behaviour Cloning Self Driving Car
- Top Projects: Web Crawler, Inventory Management System, Library Management System, Cashier Application, Forums Web Application

#### **Additional Courses**

 Online Courses: ASP.NET, Full Stack Web Development, Laravel, C#, Java, Python, Android, Fl Studio, Deep Learning, Self-Driving Car, Data Structure, JavaScript, WordPress

# Certificates

# Al Engineer Internship Certificate | Animals.ai (Link)

Helsingborg, Sweden | 08/2023 - 10/2023

- Completed an intensive internship program at Animals.Al, where I demonstrated exceptional initiative and problem-solving skills.
- Successfully completed a computer vision AI project originally scheduled for 3 months in just 2 weeks.
- Introduced and implemented an innovative approach to a project, resulting in improved efficiency and project outcomes adopted by the company.

# Lead Al Engineer Smart Lab | Toros University (Link)

Mersin, Turkey | Teknofest 2023

Online Courses: ASP.NET, Full Stack Web Development, Laravel, C#, Java, Python, Android, Fl Studio, Deep Learning, Self-Driving Car, Data Structure, JavaScript, WordPress

#### Certificate Of Completion | Udemy (Link)

Mersin, Turkey | 29.01.2023

The Complete Self-Driving Car Course – Applied Deep Learning